《阿凡达》的人物在潘多拉性交时
Okay in Avatar when they have sex in Pandora
会连接双方的马尾辫  可以推测
they hook up their ponytails, so we know their ponytails
马尾辫类似于他们的生殖器
are like their junk.
那又怎样
Yeah... so?
他们骑马或骑鸟的时候
So, when they ride horses and fly on the birds,
也会用到马尾辫
they also use their ponytails.
你到底想说什么
What's your point?
也就是说  如果我是马或者鸟
My point is, if I were a horse or a bird,
我在詹姆斯·卡梅隆身边会相当紧张
I'd be very nervous around James Cameron.
你对虚构情节如此着迷 实在让我费解
It amazes me how you constantly obsess over fictional details
现实世界中还有很多 重要的事等着你呢
when there are more important things in the real world to worry about.
比如  威廉·夏特纳怎么没出演 新的《星际迷航》电影
For example, why wasn't William Shatner in the new Star Trek movie?
谢尔顿 我刚走过行政办公室时
Hey, Sheldon. I was up in the administration office,
无意中听到了 今年大学科学奖
and I happened to overhear the name of the winner
得奖人的名字
of this year's Chancellor's Award for Science.
你又想趁机打击我
And you want to rub my nose in the fact
我的成就又被无视了吧
that my contributions are being overlooked again?
我就是理论物理界的威廉·夏特纳
I am the William Shatner of theoretical physics.
好吧  我配合你
All right, I'll play.
他们今年选了哪个 自以为是 狂妄自大的骗子
What self-important, preening fraud are they honoring this year?
我真高兴你这么问  那个人就是你
Oh, I'm so glad you asked it like that. You.
-我得奖了  -你得奖了
- I won?  - You won.
我得奖啦
I won!
太让我感到意外了
This is astonishing.
不是意外得了奖  没人比我更有资格
Not that I won the award-- no one deserves it more.
其实  我说错了 根本不意外  得奖是意料中的事
Actually, I guess I misspoke. It's not astonishing; more like inevitable.
我不知道该先做什么 要不先通知我妈
I'm not sure what to do first. Maybe I should call my mother.
我知道啦  做个自访 然后放到网上去
Wait! I know-- I'm going to conduct an interview with myself and post it online.
真替他高兴
Well, good for him.
对  理论物理界的威廉·夏特纳
Yeah, the one thing the William Shatner
最需要的就是自我膨胀
of theoretical physics needed was an ego boost.
生活大爆炸
第三季第十八集
那支长矛逼真得 就像要直接穿过咱的头啊
Didn't it look like that spear was going to go right through your skull?
才怪
No.
你不买7-11的Slurpee[饮料名] 就没眼镜戴
Hey, you didn't want a Slurpee at 7-Eleven, you don't get glasses.
肯定又是打给我道贺的
Oh, that will be another congratulatory call for me.
请静音
Uh, mute, please.
等等  火焰箭呢
Wait, wait. Hang on-- flaming arrow.
喂
Hello?
莫顿校长  你好
Oh, Chancellor Morton, how are you, sir?
对  我在等你的电话 三年前就开始了
Yes, I was expecting your call. Three years ago.
我明白
I see.
等等  如果我不想做演讲呢
Wait. What happens if I choose not to give a speech?
嗯
Uh-huh.
如果我不想放弃奖项呢
And if I don't want to forfeit the award?
好  您现在是箭在弦上  不得不发
Well, you've got that tied up in a neat little bow.
好吧
All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
有状况
Problem.
咋了
What?
他们要我在宴会上做演讲
They expect me to give a speech at the banquet.
我不会做演讲
I can't give a speech.
不  你弄错了 你一直都滔滔不绝
Well, no, you're mistaken. You give speeches all the time.
你是不会闭嘴
What you can't do is shut up.
看电影前
Yeah, before the movie,
你说了20分钟为啥鳄梨酱变棕色了
you did 20 minutes on why guacamole turns brown.
你说话的时候  它就变棕色了
It turned brown while you were talking.
我在小群体面前能自如讲话
I am perfectly comfortable speaking to small groups.
但没法在大群体面前演讲
I cannot speak to large crowds.
你的大群体怎么定义
What, to you, is a large crowd?
大到能把我踩死的那种
Any group big enough to trample me to death.
按经验估计是36个成人或70个儿童
General rule of thumb is 36 adults or 70 children.
谢尔顿  恭喜恭喜
Sheldon, congratulations.
从店里给你带了芝士蛋糕
Brought you a cheesecake from work.
这是给你庆祝得奖的
You know, 'cause of your award,
不是因为小工对着它打了喷嚏
not because a busboy sneezed on it.
-我不接受奖项了  -为什么
- I'm not accepting the award.  - Why not?
因为伟大的谢尔顿居然会怯场
Turns out the great Sheldon Cooper has stage fright.
那也没有理由退出啊
That's no reason to back out.
我以前在高中时 得了个很大的奖
You know, I once got a pretty big honor in high school,
而我很怕面对一大群人
and I was terrified about appearing in front of a big crowd,
但我挺过来了  知道吗
but I went through with it, and you know what?
作为玉米皇后团的成员之一
The world looked pretty darn good
坐在福特F150后面放的干草堆上
sitting on a haystack in the back of a Ford F-150
那是相当的风光啊
as a member of the Corn Queen's court.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会牢记在心的
Yeah, I'll bear that in mind
如果我被提名乡巴佬和平奖的话
if I'm ever nominated for the Hillbilly Peace Prize.
谢尔顿  你小题大做了
Sheldon, you're being ridiculous.
是吗
Am I?
我给你们讲个故事
Let me tell you a story.
咱现在就需要70个儿童
Where's 70 children when you need them?
我14岁时以Summa cum laude的成绩从大学毕业
I was 14 and graduating summa cum laude from college.
Summa cum laude在拉丁语里是指最高荣誉
"Summa cum laude" is Latin for "with highest honors."
你要是能跳过 没人问的东西就好了
I just love how you always skip over the part where no one asks.
我要在毕业典礼上做致词
I was valedictorian and expected to give an address.
我到现在还记得当时
Even now, I can remember that moment
我走上讲台  看着人群
when I walked up to the podium and looked out at the crowd.
台下数以千计的人
There must have been thousands of people.
我的心开始剧烈跳动
My heart started pounding in my chest.
然后开始大口呼气
I began to hyperventilate.
视力渐渐模糊  还没来得及...
My vision became blurry, and before I knew it...
晕啊
Oh, dear.
老天
Oh, my God.
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
谢尔顿  你没事吧
Sheldon, are you okay?
表踩我啊
Don't trample me.
拜托  妈妈
Come on, Mother.
你知道我为啥不接受奖项
You know why I can't accept the award.
恕我直言  我不觉得祈祷会有用
With all due respect, I don't think praying will help.
没  我没听过那首 "主啊  请掌控这命运之轮"
No, I have not heard the song, "Jesus, Take the Wheel."
不用不用 你不需要唱给我听
No, no... You don't need to start singing it.
好  我会在iTunes上下载的  妈妈
Yes, I'll buy it on the iTunes, Mother.
再见  妈妈
Good-bye, Mother.
各位好
Hello.
坐啊  我们想和你谈谈
Sit down. We want to talk to you.
我是有麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
我妈妈给你们打电话了
Did my mother call you?
坐就是了
Just sit.
我们能帮你克服怯场的问题
We think we can help you with your stage fright.
我深表怀疑
Oh, I doubt that.
我比你们智商都高 我都没想出办法呢
I haven't figured out a way, and I'm much smarter than all of you.
是的  可我们几个的智商加起来肯定比你高
Yes, but you're not smarter than all of us put together.
不好意思 还是我高
Oh, I'm sorry. That is what I meant.
好吧  你的问题是 你想孤军奋战
Okay. Your problem is, you're trying to do this all by yourself.
我们可以帮你  当你的队友
We can help you. We can be your team.
就像  X教授和X战警
Like, uh, Professor Xavier and his X-Men.
我确实挺喜欢《X战警》
I do like the X-Men.
我看过《X战警》吗
Did I see X-Men?
看过啊  我们上周才看的 你还说你喜欢呢
Yeah, we watched it last week. You said you liked it.
亲爱的  说话又不用付钱
Oh. I say a lot of things, sweetie.
怎么样啊  谢尔顿
So, how about it, Sheldon?
不好说
I don't know.
如果你们是X战警  那你们的超能力是什么
If you're my X-Men, what are your powers?
这个  我会带你去购物 帮你选一套超赞的西装
Okay. Well, I am going to take you shopping, get you a nice suit.
能让你更自信
Might give you more confidence.
确切来说这不叫变异  光凭这点你不可能
That's not exactly a mutation that would get you
进到X教授专为天赋异禀的年轻人开设的学校
into Xavier's School for Gifted Youngsters,
不过继续
but go on.
莱纳德
Leonard?
我可以对你进行心理分析
I thought I could try to analyze you
然后找出让你如此焦虑的根源
and get to the root of your anxiety.
你凭什么觉得你能读懂我的内心呢
What qualifies you to attempt to understand my mind?
我妈是一位杰出的精神病专家
My mother is a highly regarded psychiatrist,
而且自从她指责我过于依赖母乳开始
and I've been in therapy ever since she accused me
我就一直在接受治疗
of breast-feeding codependently.
拉杰说他可以教你
Raj says he can teach you...
什么名字来着
What did you call it?
我记不住  一些扯淡的印度冥想
I don't know-- some Indian meditation crap.
明白了 由于前三位的水准 都严重不靠谱
I see. Well, I assume, since the rest of you have set the bar so low,
我想你们是把最睿智的办法放到了最后
you're saving the most impressive contribution for last.
说吧  霍华德 惊我一下
Go ahead, Howard. Dazzle me.
我的超能力就是我可以
My power is the ability to pretend
假装我很在意你这尿频尿急类的鬼问题
like I give a damn about your piddily-ass problems.
而且我能一直装下去  伙计
And that's 24-seven, buddy.
我很感激你如此做作
And I appreciate the pretense.
怎么样啊  谢尔顿
So, what do you say, Sheldon?
我们是你的X战警吗
Are we your X-Men?
不是
No.
X战警这名字来源于X教授的姓氏
The X-Men were named for the "X" in Charles Xavier.
既然我叫谢尔顿·库珀  那你们就是C战警(与精液谐音)
Since I am Sheldon Cooper, you will be my C-Men.
这名字可不怎么好听
Oh, that's not a good name.
好了  谢尔顿 我将引导你进行
Okay, Sheldon. I'm going to be leading you
一系列的冥想练习
through a series of meditation exercises.
这些方法是从古代印度大师那里
These methods come from the ancient gurus of India
传承下来的  也帮我克服了自己的恐惧
and have helped me overcome my own fears.
可你还是不敢和女人说话
And yet, you can't speak to women.
确实  不过托冥想的福  我可以和女人
True, but thanks to meditation, I am able to stay
呆在同一房间  而且不会被吓到尿裤子
in the same room with them without urinating.
现在  闭上双眼
Now... close your eyes.
好的  不过不许打我
Okay, but don't punch me.
什么
What?
小时候  我姐姐会对我说
When I was little, my sister would say to me,
"闭上双眼  惊喜出现"
"Close your eyes, you'll get a surprise,"
然后她就会给我一拳
and then she'd punch me.
我不会打你的
I'm not going to punch you.
我姐姐以前也这么说的
That's what my sister used to say.
你到底还练不练了
Do you want to do this or not?
抱歉  请继续
I'm sorry. Proceed.
好的
All right.
想象你正身处一个 最有家的感觉的地方
Imagine yourself in the one place you feel most at home.
是哪里呢
Where is that?
模拟城市[一款游戏]
Sim City.
更确切地说  是我设计的模拟城市
More specifically, the Sim City I designed--
谢尔顿奥波利斯
Sheldonopolis.
好的  你身处谢尔顿奥波利斯
Okay, you're in Sheldonopolis.
确切的地点是哪
Where exactly?
谢尔顿广场  谢尔顿之塔
Sheldon Square? Sheldon Towers?
还是人称谢尔顿勇士之家的谢尔顿运动场
Sheldon Stadium, home of the Fighting Sheldons?
随你喜欢
Whatever you like.
不是说你引导我冥想吗
I thought this was supposed to be a guided meditation.
好吧  你在谢尔顿广场
Fine. You're in Sheldon Square.
是吗  这个季节吗
Really? This time of year?
那可有点冷
It's a bit nippy.
那就穿件毛衣
Then, put on a sweater.
那我可以去市中心的
Suppose I could run downtown
谢尔玛买一件
and pick up something at Shel-Mart.
随便啊  去买件毛衣就是了
Yeah, whatever. Just go buy a sweater.
好处就是谢尔玛是我开的
You know, the nice thing about Shel-Mart is I own it,
所以我买东西85折
so I get a 15% discount.
还不都你说了算 痛快拿件毛衣就行了
You own the damn thing. Just take a freaking sweater!
上一季度我根本没有盈利
Look, I didn't turn a profit last quarter
就是因为我肆无忌惮地拿东西不给钱
by taking product off the shelves willy-nilly.
好吧
All right.
你买了件毛衣  现在你在谢尔顿广场
You've paid for a sweater, and you're in Sheldon Square.
等等
Hang on.
是开衫的  我得扣上扣子
It's a cardigan. I have to button it.
不会吧
Oh, no.
又怎么了
What now?
一个类似哥斯拉的怪物正在接近城市
A Godzilla-like monster is approaching the city.
我得把我的市民转移到安全区
I have to get my people to safety.
谢尔顿奥波利斯的市民们  我是你们的市长
People of Sheldonopolis, this is your mayor.
跟着我
Follow me.
小孩子要是跑不了  就别管他们了
If the children can't run, leave them behind.
哎哟妈呀  模拟恐怖效果贼棒
Oh, the simulated horror!
拉杰
Raj?
我就知道
Just as I suspected.
什么冥想不过是噱头
Meditation is nothing but hokum.
我相当质疑你的说法
I question your premise.
要防止我在满屋子人面前晕倒
How is a new suit going to prevent me
买套新西装有个毛用了
from passing out in front of a ballroom full of people?
那会让你充满自信
It'll give you confidence.
只要我倍感压力时
You know, sometimes when I'm feeling all stressed out
我就会去买件可爱上衣
about something, I go out and buy a cute top
或漂漂裙裙  如此一来就会容光焕发
or a fun skirt and I have a whole new outlook on life.
你傻的啊  难道你没意识到 你只是换了皮囊  内压犹在啊
Don't you eventually realize you're just the same stressed out person
穿可爱上装和漂漂裙裙有啥用
in a cute top or a fun skirt?
是的  所以还要买鞋子
Yeah, that's when I buy shoes.
我们来选选
Now, let's see what we've got.
这件帅气
This is nice.
这件就一个颜色
It's only one color.
是啊  咋了
Yeah, so?
就一个颜色还这么贵  岂不是亏了
That's a lot of money for only one color.
好吧
Fine.
你自己选自己喜欢的
Why don't you pick out what you like.
这件很犀利
This is pretty sharp.
不 没门儿
No. You're wrong.
这件够劲
This is great.
我六岁时也有件差不多样式的
I had a suit like this when I was six.
好吧  这件绝对无可挑剔
Okay, I think we have a winner.
靠  你哪儿弄来的这件
Where the hell'd you find that?
舞会礼服柜台
In the prom department.
这也太可笑了
It's ridiculous.
玉米皇后团前团员没资格说这话吧
Says the former member of the Corn Queen's Court.
去试试这件再说
Please just try this one on.
好吧 现在不管我穿啥 和之前的相比都只能相形见拙了
Okay. But anything I put on now is only going to suffer in comparison.
这太荒唐了 简直像个小丑
This is absurd. I look like a clown.
谢尔顿
So, Sheldon...
你最近如何
...how you doing?
你就这样开始心理治疗吗
That's how you start a psychotherapy session?
居然问这种蠢问题
"How am I doing?"
我本来满心期待进行一场
I was promised a riverboat journey
对自我潜意识的探寻之旅
into the jungles of my subconscious.
结果呢  我都听到什么鬼问题啊
Instead, I get the same question I hear
拉尔夫餐厅切香肠的女招待都问得出来
from the lady who slices my bologna at Ralph's.
抱歉  我重来
I'm sorry, I'll start again.
我还是说说我的梦境吧 对你有帮助吗
Would it be helpful to you if I told you about my dreams?
我也不知道  也许吧
Um, I don't know, maybe.
我最近做了个梦 梦到我变成了巨人
I recently had a dream that I was a giant.
但周围的东西还是原来的比例
But everything around me was to scale,
所以相比之下没什么差别
so it all looked normal.
既然周围东西都没什么变化 你怎么知道自己变成了巨人
How did you know you were a giant if everything was to scale?
我穿着条型号为一百万的裤子
I was wearing size a million pants.
我们还是来自由谈话吧
Why don't we just talk?
自由谈话疗法 经典精神分析疗法  不错
The talking cure. Classical Freudian. Good choice.
我补充一点可能会有所帮助
If it will help speed things along,
我做标准罗夏墨迹测验的结果是
uh, my answers to the standard Rorschach ink blot test are:
图A  蝙蝠  图B  蝙蝠 图C  蝙蝠
A) a bat, B) a bat, c) a bat,
图D  我爸想用皮下注射器杀死我妈
and D) my father killing my mother with a hypodermic needle.
还是我来说吧
Why don't I just start?
这种事时有发生 人们难以接受一项荣誉
Sometimes people have trouble accepting accolades
那是因为在潜意识中 他们自觉不配拥有
if, on a subconscious level, they don't feel they deserve them.
会不会你的原因也是如此呢
Do you think maybe that's what's happening here?
真的假的  莱纳德
Really, Leonard?
你是想把阿德勒学说中的
You're just going to try to recycle Adler's doctrine
自卑情结套用在我身上吗
of the inferiority complex?
这连拉尔夫餐厅的女招待都知道
I could probably get that from the woman at Ralph's.
说不定她还会白送我芝士呢
And she'd let me taste some pieces of cheese for free.
但这可能是问题所在
But it could be part of your problem.
我举个例子吧
Let me give you an example.
我8岁时
When I was eight,
我的一个项目  "古典音乐有助青豆生长"
I won a ribbon at the science fair
在科技展上得了奖  授予了我一条勋带
for my project, "Do Lima Beans Grow Better to Classical Music."
但我妈妈却说
But my mother pointed out
这和我哥哥以前的研究  "摇滚乐有害于青豆生长"
that it was just a rehash of my brother's earlier
根本没差  只不过换汤不换药
"Do Lima Beans Grow Worse to Rock 'n' Roll."
我倍受打击  于是把勋带退了回去
I felt so guilty, I gave the ribbon back.
你感觉如何
And how did that make you feel?
糟透了
Terrible.
对那个研究我付出了很多心血
I worked really hard on that project.
我整晚都不睡  就对着青豆芽
I stayed up all night singing the clown's aria from Pagliacci
唱《丑角》里的咏叹调[莱昂卡瓦洛作曲]
to a lima bean sprout.
继续说
Go on.
这又不是我的错
It wasn't my fault.
我不知道我哥的研究
I had never seen my brother's project.
我妈之前本可以告诉我
And my mother could've told me before
她却在颁奖典礼上当着众人面说出来
instead of at the ceremony in front of everyone.
这么说 你很生你母亲的气咯
So, I hear you saying you're angry with your mother.
当然气  我恨死她了
Damn right, I'm angry with my mother.
行行好嘛  我那会儿才8岁
For God's sake, I was eight years old.
她却这么当众羞辱我
She humiliated me.
就是在那之后  我又开始尿床
That's when the bed-wetting started again.
多谢了  莱纳德
Thank you, Leonard.
谢什么啊
For what?
像你这样受了如此打击
If someone as damaged as you
还能每天早上从床上爬起来
can find his way to crawl out of bed each morning,
我想小小一个颁奖典礼  应该不成问题
I think I can face a simple award ceremony.
等等  就这样吗 不是该有一整个小时的吗
Wait, that's it? I thought we had a whole hour!
女士们先生们  晚上好 我是莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德博士
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. My name is Dr. Leonard Hofstadter,
很荣幸向各位隆重介绍
and it is my very great honor to introduce
本年度大学科学奖得主
the winner of this year's Chancellor's award for Science
我的好友谢尔顿·库珀博士
and my good friend, Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
但在此之前
But before I do,
请允许我先宣读下谢尔顿母亲的来信
I'd like to share with you a letter from Sheldon's mother,
很遗憾她今晚未能亲临
who couldn't be here tonight.
很温馨了  是吧  他妈妈给他写了封信
Isn't that nice? His mother sent him a letter.
他为自己儿子感到自豪  真想知道那会是什么感觉...
She's proud of him. I wonder what that feels like...
亲爱的谢利  她都是这么叫他的  谢利  这是个昵称
"Dear Shelly." that's what she calls him. Shelly-- it's a pet name.
知道我妈给我取的什么昵称吗  莱纳德
You know what my mother's pet name for me is? Leonard.
我又离题了
But I digress.
亲爱的谢利...
"Dear Shelly..."
天哪
Oh, dear.
你怎么了
What's the matter?
我有点晕
I'm getting dizzy.
别担心
Don't worry.
你的C战警们(精液 semen)都守护着你
You're surrounded by your C-Men.
我做不到
I can't do this.
我要晕倒了
I'm going to faint.
给  喝点这个  能让你放松
Here, drink this.It'll relax you.
酒吗
Alcohol?
-我不喝酒的  -好吧  那你晕吧
- I don't drink alcohol. - Fine, faint.
没觉得有何不同  这酒根本没用
I don't feel different.This alcohol is defective.
给  看这个有没有用
Here, see if this one works.
首先 那是完全不同的实验主题
First of all, the projects were totally different.
我的实验证明  培植青豆时  给它们放古典乐
I was showing that classical music nurtures lima beans
能促进它们生长  但我妈根本不听我的
and makes them grow, but my mother didn't hear me.
想知道精心培育能不能促进成长吗
If you'd like to look at the relationship between nurturing and growth,
我想郑重指出  我哥哥比我高了整整八英寸[20cm]
I'd like to point out that my brother is eight inches taller than me.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
对了
right.
女士们先生们  欢迎我们的贵宾  谢尔顿·库珀博士
Ladies and gentlemen, our guest of honor Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
谢了小矮人  下面我接手就行了
Thanks, shorty, I'll take it from here.
好了  大家准备好来点乐子了吗
All right, you people ready to have some fun?
你们都对微积分有基本认识
You have a basic understanding of differential calculus
并至少学过一年代数拓扑吧
and at least one year of algebraic topology?
好吧  下面是笑话时间
Well, then here come the jokes.
鸡为什么要穿过默比乌斯带
Why did the chicken cross the Mobius strip?
为了回到同一侧  逗你玩呢
To get to the same side-- bazinga!
还有  一个中子走进家酒吧问道 酒多少钱一杯
All right, a neutron walks into a bar and asks, "How much for a drink?"
酒保回答  你买吗  免费(无电荷)
The bartender says, "For you, no charge."
有人在吗
Hello?
我知道你们在的
I know you're out there.
能听到你们代谢氧气  排出二氧化碳的声音
I can hear you metabolizing oxygen and expelling carbon dioxide.
观众中好像不乏学术权威啊
Looks like we have some academic dignitaries in the audience.
地质学系的兰德尔教授
Dr. Randall from the geology department--
唯一一位别人说他(研究花岗岩)"花岗岩脑袋"  他还得笑纳的人
only man who's happy when they take his work for granite.
巴扎嘿
Ba-da cha!
当然  我是在拿地质学家开涮
I kid the geologists, of course,
那只是因为我压根就没把那当回事儿
but it's only 'cause I have no respect for the field.
下面我们来谈点严肃话题
Let's get serious for a moment.
我们今天为何齐聚于此
Why are we all here?
因为我们是科学家
'Cause we're scientists.
科学家是研究什么的
And what do scientists study?
宇宙
The universe.
宇宙由何构成
And what's the universe made of?
很高兴你提这问题
I am so glad you asked.
有锑  砷  铝  硒
There's antimony, arsenic, aluminum, selenium
有氢  氧  氮  铼
And hydrogen and oxygen and nitrogen and rhenium
还有镍  钕  镎  锗
And nickel, neodymium, neptunium, germanium
一起唱
Everybody!
还有铁  镅
And iron, americium
钌  铀  铕  锆
Ruthenium, uranium, europium, zirconium,
镥  钒
Lutetium, vanadium
亚洲人唱
Just the Asians!
还有镧和锇
And lanthanum and osmium
砹和镭
And astatine and radium...
佩妮  莱纳德
Penny, Leonard.
你们能不能帮我答疑解惑
Would you be able to answer some questions
昨天晚上我到底怎么回事
I'm having about the events of last night?
当然
Sure.
问题一
Question one...
我的裤子上哪去了
where are my pants?
你可以上YouTube看一下
You might want to check YouTube.
怎么找
What do I search?
已经缓冲好了  直接点开看吧
It's already loaded. Just hit play.
好了各位  让我们来聊聊数学吧
All right, people, let's get down to the math.
仅仅用三维的思考方式  会限制我们的想象力
It is only three dimensional thinking that limits our imagination.
我能从头上脱了裤子吗
Can I take my pants off over my head?
当然不行
Of course not.
还有我身体挡着的  [视频名：物理学家斯文扫地]
My body's in the way.
但只要能进入更高维度
But if we had access to higher dimensions,
就能通过第四维度
we could move our pants around our bodies
让裤子绕着身体转圈
through the fourth dimension
以后就再没脱裤子这么一说了
and our days of dropping trousers would be over.
天哪
Oh, Lord...
真是丢人丢到家了
This couldn't be any more humiliating.
还没完呢
Give it a minute.
现在  在座的各位天文学家们
Now, for the astronomers in the audience,
准备好看看月亮背面吧
get ready to see the dark side of the moon.
还有天王星在此[Uranus 谐音your anus菊花]
And here's Uranus.